kelvinpowertools.com 2019-05-25

# Privacy Policy - KelvinPowerTools.com

### 1\. Who We Are

We are Kelvin Power Tools Ltd. We accept responsibility as the Data Controller for all of the information that we collect.

### 2\. Your Privacy

Throughout our dealings with you, we may collect and/or process information about you.

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We will use your information in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations which relate to data protection and privacy.

By using our services, you agree to the collection and processing of your information in accordance with this policy.

This policy (along with our **_Terms and Conditions_** ) tells you:

  * What information we may collect about you
  * Why we collect this information
  * How we may use this information
  * How long we will keep this information for
  * Who we may disclose this information to
  * Your rights regarding this information
  * How you can contact us

### 3\. The Information We Collect

Throughout our dealings with you, we may collect and/or process the following information about you:

  * We may ask you to provide us with information which allows us to identify you as an individual ("Personal Data"). Personal Data may include, but is not limited to: 
    * Your name
    * Your email address
    * Your telephone number
    * Your address and postcode
    * If you are placing an order; your payment card number, expiry date and CVV number
    * If you are creating an account on our website; a username and password
  * We may collect information regarding how you access and use our website ("Usage Data"). Usage Data may include, but is not limited to: 
    * Your device’s IP address
    * Unique device identifiers
    * Your browser type and version
    * The pages that you visit
    * The length of time you spend on each page
    * The date and time of your visit
    * Other diagnostic data
  * We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small files which are sent to and stored on your device when you visit a website. These files contain data about your activity on said website. You can restrict or block cookies through your browser settings, however, you may not be able to access certain parts of our website if you do so.

### 4\. Why We Collect this Information

We may collect and/or process this information about you for the following reasons:

  * When you place an order, we need your Personal Data to allow us to take payment for and fulfil your order
  * When you purchase certain products, we may need your Personal Data to allow us to register them for an extended warranty with the manufacturer
  * When you purchase certain products, we may need your Personal Data to allow us to claim a discount voucher on your behalf from the manufacturer
  * When you create an account on our website, we need your Personal Data for security reasons, for example, to allow us to identify you
  * When you contact us for any reason, we need your Personal Data to allow us to identify and respond to you
  * When you sign up to receive our marketing communications, we need your Personal Data to allow us to fulfil your request
  * We collect Usage Data and use cookies on our website to help us analyse and improve our services

### 5\. How We Use this Information

We use the information that we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * **To communicate with you about your order for a product or service** : This is a contractual necessity. We use your Personal Data to meet our obligations under our contract with you, for example, to deliver your order.
  * **To register certain products you purchase for an extended warranty** : This is a contractual necessity. We use your Personal Data to meet our obligations under our contract with you.
  * **To register certain products you purchase for a discount voucher** : This is a contractual necessity. We use your Personal Data to meet our obligations under our contract with you.
  * **To respond to you when you contact us for any reason, for example, for customer support** : This is in our legitimate interests. We use your Personal Data to communicate with you.
  * **To notify you about changes to our services** : This is in our legitimate interests. We use your Personal Data to keep you up to date with information regarding our services.
  * **To contact you about leaving a review for a product or service once your order has been fulfilled** : This is in our legitimate interests. We use your Personal Data to ask you to provide feedback regarding the product or service you received from us so that we can analyse and improve said product or service.
  * **To send you information about our products and services, including special offers, discounts, free gifts and events** : This is in our legitimate interests. We use your Personal Data to send you this information where you have previously purchased similar products or services from us and we think that this information may be of interest to you. You can opt-out of receiving our email communications by clicking on the unsubscribe link that is provided in any marketing email you receive from us.
  * **To contact you for market research purposes** : This is in our legitimate interests. We use your Personal Data to help us analyse and improve our services.
  * **To track and analyse your activity on our website to improve and tailor your online experience; investigate, detect or prevent technical issues on our website; or investigate, detect or prevent any wrongdoing or criminal activity on our website** : This is in our legitimate interests. We use your Personal Data, Usage Data and cookies to help us analyse and improve our services.
  * **To carry out security checks to investigate, detect or prevent any wrongdoing or criminal activity** : This is in our legitimate interests. We use your Personal Data for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### 6\. How Long We Retain this Information For

We only retain the information that we collect from you for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which we are using it. We may retain your information for longer if we are required to for legal or regulatory reasons.

### 7\. Who We May Disclose this Information To

We may disclose your information to third parties in the following circumstances:

  * We use third-party services for payment processing (“Payment Processors”). We do not store your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our Payment Processors whose use of your Personal Data is governed by their privacy policy. The Payment Processors we work with are: 
    * **WorldPay** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](https://www.worldpay.com/uk/worldpay-privacy-notice "WorldPay Privacy Policy").
    * **Sage Pay** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](https://www.sagepay.co.uk/policies/privacy-policy "Sage Pay Privacy Policy").
    * **PayPal** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full "PayPal Privacy Policy").
  * We may use third parties to facilitate our services, to provide our services on our behalf, or to assist us in monitoring and analysing how our services are used ("Service Providers"). Our Service Providers only have access to your information needed to perform their functions. They are obliged to not disclose or use it for any other purpose. The Service Providers we work with include but are not limited to: 
    * **Google Analytics** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en "Google Privacy Policy").
    * **Google AdWords** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en "Google Privacy Policy").
  * We register certain products that you purchase on your behalf with the manufacturer in order for you to receive an extended warranty. We only disclose the necessary information they need to provide you with the warranty and they are obliged to not disclose or use it for any other purpose. The manufacturers that this applies to are: 
    * **Festool** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](https://www.festool.co.uk/legal-information/data-protection "Festool Privacy Policy").
    * **Honda** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](http://www.honda.co.uk/industrial/useful-links/privacy-policy.html "Honda Privacy Policy").
  * We claim discount vouchers for certain products that you purchase on your behalf from the manufacturer in order for you to receive a discount. We only disclose the necessary information they need to provide you with the discount voucher and they are obliged to not disclose or use it for any other purpose. The manufacturers that this applies to are: 
    * **Festool** : Their privacy policy can be viewed [**_here_**](https://www.festool.co.uk/legal-information/data-protection "Festool Privacy Policy").
  * We are required to do so by law
  * In response to valid requests from public authorities
  * To investigate, detect or prevent any possible wrongdoing or criminal activity - this includes for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction
  * To enforce or apply our **_Terms and Conditions_**  or any other agreements we have with you or otherwise concerning you
  * To protect our rights, property or safety, or those of our customers, employees or other third parties
  * To our insurers if a claim is made or could be made against us
  * To the prospective seller or buyer if we sell or buy any business or assets
  * To the other business if this business is integrated with another

### 8\. Where this Information May be Processed

Your information may be transferred to, processed in or stored in one or more countries outside of the UK where the data protection laws may differ.

If you are located outside of the UK and use our services, we will transfer your information to the UK and process it here where the data protection laws may differ.

In these circumstances, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your information is adequately protected in accordance with the law.

### 9\. The Security of this Information

The security of your Personal Data is important to us.

All of the Personal Data that you provide us with is stored on our secure servers.

Any payment transactions are encrypted. As explained in section 7 of this Privacy Policy, we do not store your payment card details.

The contact form on our website is encrypted.

If you have an online account, you are responsible for keeping your password confidential. We ask that you do not share your password with anyone and we recommend that you do not use the same password for different online accounts. We also ask that you log out of your account when you have finished your session to prevent any unauthorised access to your account, for example, on a shared device.

We do our best to protect your Personal Data, however we cannot guarantee its absolute security. No method of information transmission over the internet or electronic storage is completely secure. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent any unauthorised access.

### 10\. Your Rights

You have the right to:

  * Access and receive a copy of the Personal Data that we hold about you
  * Request that we correct any inaccuracies in your Personal Data. You can update your Personal Data in your account settings on our website. If you are unable to do so, contact us and we will make the required changes for you.
  * Request that we delete your Personal Data if there is no legitimate reason for us to retain it
  * Request that we delete your online account if you no longer wish to have one
  * Request that we do not use your Personal Data for marketing purposes

**_Contact us here_** to make any of the above requests. We may ask you for proof of your identity before responding to your request.

### 11\. Links to Other Websites

Our website may contain links to other websites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be redirected to a website that is not governed by this Privacy Policy. We strongly advise that you review the privacy policy of every website you visit. We have no control over the privacy policy of any third party website and the way in which they process your information. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for any issues that arise in connection with the way in which a third party processes your information.

### 12\. Integration of the Trusted Shops Trustbadge

Following an order, the Trusted Shops Trustbadge is incorporated into this web page in order to display our eventually collected reviews. In balancing the various interests, this serves to safeguard our legitimate interests in an optimised marketing of our goods and services. The trustbadge and the services advertised are provided by Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15C, 50823 Köln. Whenever a trustbadge is called up, the web server automatically stores a so-called server log file which contains, for example, your IP address, the date and time of retrieval, the data volume transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the retrieval. This access data will not be evaluated and will be automatically overwritten seven days after your visit to the page. Other personal information will only be transferred to Trusted Shops if you decide, after completing an order, to use Trusted Shops products or have already registered for their use. In this case, the contractual agreement between you and Trusted Shops applies.

### 13\. Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, you can **_contact us here_**.

### 14\. Updates to Our Privacy Policy

If we make any changes to our Privacy Policy, we will notify you by updating this page and, where appropriate, contacting you via email.
